Guide to The Leo Deaner Radical Left-Wing Publications collection, 1890-2017 LAC0011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets by topic, 1890-2017; Series 3
  - Movements, 1923-2017; Series 3 Subseries 3
    - Movements, 1961-1980; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Consumption Domestic Imperialism: a New Left Introduction to the Political Economy of American Capitalism Published by Movement for a Democratic Society (MDS Pamphlet no. 1); Is there a Student Movement? By Otto Feinstein Reprinted from New University Thought Summer 1961; U.S. Imperialism by David Gilbert and David Loud Published by Students for Democratic Society; Wanted Fast Eddie for Helping Himself & the Rich to our Tax Money Edited by Ike Mezo, Griever USWA Local 65; Revolutionary Age, vol. 1, no. 2 (1968) Published by Freedom Socialist Publications; 2…3…Many, vol. 1, no. 13 (Summer 1971) Published by Committee of Returned Volunteers; Two Socialists view the New Left by William Allen & Paul Feldman; Autopsy on the A.M.A.: an Analysis of Health-Care Delivery Systems in America Published by Student Research Facility; NUC Newsletter vol. 4, no., 1 (Sept. 15, 1970)-v. 4, no. 6 (Dec. 5, 1970), vol. 4, no. 8 (Jan. 10, 1971)-v. 4, no. 10 (Feb. 10, 1971), vol. 4, no. 12 (Mar. 30, 1971), vol. 4, no. 16 (June 1, 1971)-v. 4, no. 17 (July 4, 1971) Published by New University Conference
    - Movements, 1969-1992; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 119, Folder 4)
      Power of Women and the Subversion of the Community by Mariarosa Dalla Costa, and Woman's Place by Selma James, 2nd edition Published by Falling Wall Press and a Group of Individuals from the Women's Liberation Movement in England and Italy; Abortion: a Woman's Right to Choose by Claudine Holt; Pioneers of Women's Liberation by Joyce Cowley; Legal Rights of Battered Women in California Published by Voluntary Legal Services Program, State Bar of California; Selected Differences in the Life Chances of Men and Women in the United States by Howard J. Ehrlich (Research Group One Report no. 13); Women in Health Written by Women's Work Project Published by Union for Radical Political Economics; Problems of Women's Liberation: a Marxist Approach by Evelyn Reed; Abortion without Apology: a Radical History for the 1990's by Ninia Baehr (South End Press Pamphlet no. 8); Women and Psychology Published by Cambridge-Goddard Graduate School for Social Change
    - Movements, 1961-1999; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 120, Folder 2)
      Contents in folder include publications about Anti-Vietnam War
      Vietnam: Impressions of a People's War by Rae Murphy Published by Canadian Tribune; Join the U.S. Committee to Free Political Prisoners in South Viet-Nam [flyer]; Simple Art of Murder: Antipersonnel Weapons and their Developers by Eric Prokosch Published by NARMIC [National Action/Research on the Military Industrial Complex]; Wisconsin Draft Resistance Union by Bob Gabriner and Barbara Baran Reprinted from The Movement; Vietnam U.S. Imperialism and US: Strike by Dan Gilbarg; Vietnam and the Pacific Rim Strategy by Peter Wiley Published by Bay Area Radical Education Project; Organizing for Nonviolent Direct Action by Charles C. Walker; Pentagon Papers Trial Published by Pentagon Papers Peace Project; Immediate Withdrawal vs Negotiations? By Caroline Jenness; by Charlotte Pomerantz and Harold Kaplan Published by Labor Committee for Peace in Vietnam; Annual Dinner and Peace Award Ceremony, May 1, 1999, Published by War Resisters League; Brief Account of Vietnam's Struggle for Independence: America's Longest War by Rachelle Marshall Published by Women's International League for Peace and Freedom; United States in /Vietnam: a Preliminary Report on International Law and War Crimes Published by Stanford War Crimes Study Group; Case for Civil Disobedience Issued by New England Committee for Nonviolent Action; Selective Service System or, the Manpower Channelers by Peter Henig; Not Since the Romans Salted the Land: Chemical Warfare in S.E. Asia by J.B. Neilands, A.H. Westing, G.H. Orians, E.W. Pfeiffer Supreme Court must Hear this Case! Issued by Defense Committee to Defend Juan Farinas; Leaf Abscission? By Ngo Vinh Long Reprinted from Bulletin of Concerned Asian Scholars; Kent State May 4 Memorial [flyers]; No Peace/no Honor Published by Indochina Peace Campaign
    - Movements, 1933-1945; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 120, Folder 3)
      Youth and Fascism by O. Kuusinen Issued by 7th World Congress of the Communist International; Work of the Seventh Congress by D.Z. Manuilsky; Rise of Socialism in the Soviet Union: Report by D.Z. Manuilsky Issued by 7th World Congress of the Communist International; United Front Against Fascism by Georgi Dimitroff (Marxist Pamphlets no. 3); Fight for Peace: Report on the Preparations for Imperialist War and the Tasks of the Communist International Delivered August 13, 1935, by M. Ercoli Issued by 7th World Congress of the Communist International; Struggle against the Imperialist War by Georgi Dimitroff; George Dimitroff with an Introduction by Earl Browder
    - Movements, 1967-2005; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 120, Folder 4)
      . Introducing the Freedom Socialist Party; Hurricane Katrina: the Crime and the Tragedy Published Jointly by Socialist Actin and Labor Standard; Richard Kirk's Revolutionary Integration the Dialectics of Black Liberation Published as Revolutionary Age, vol. 1, no 1 (1968); Claiming our Identities by Demanding our Rights: Greetings to the 3rd National Third World/People of Color Lesbian/Gay Conference and the San Francisco Lesbian and Gay Freedom Day Parade [flyer]; Organizer's Report to the FSP Conference: 1967-1969: a Crucial Phase in the Struggle for a Revolutionary Party Issued by Freedom Socialist Party; Victory for Socialist Feminism: Organizer's Report to the 1969 FSP Conference Published by Freedom Socialist Party; Victory for Socialist Feminism: Organizer's Report to the 1969 Freedom Socialist Party Conference: 1967-1969 A Crucial Phrase [sic] in the Struggle for a Revolutionary Party, New Introduction by Cindy Gipple, 2nd edition; Victory for Socialist Feminism: Organizer's Report to the 1969 Freedom Socialist Party Conference:, New Introduction by Cindy Gipple, 2nd edition with Revisions; Putting it All Together: Socialist Feminism and the Gay Movement: Organizing Materials from the Seattle Struggle, Compiled by Radical Women & the Freedom Socialist Party
    - Movements, 1972-2005; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include: publications about Marxism-Leninism
      On the General Program for the Restoration of Capitalism: One of Three Documents Written in 1975 under the Direction of the Arch unrepentant capitalist-roader in the Chinese Communist Party, Teng Hsiao-ping, for the all-round Reversal of the Verdicts of the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution; Dialectics of Black Power by Robert I. Allen Published by Weekly Guardian (Guardian Pamphlet); How to Advance the Struggle Against Social-Chauvinism Published by Central Organization of U.S. Marxist-Leninists; Greensboro Massacre: Labor Under Fire Published by Greensboro Justice Fund; P.S.I. Political and Mass Line Published by Peoples Socialist International; Communist Work in the Labor Movement Published by October League; War in Indochina by Irwin Silber; Myth of Capitalism Reborn: a Marxist Critique of Theories of Capitalist Restoration in the USSR by Michael Goldfield, Melvin Rothenberg Published by the Soviet Union Study Project; Capitalism's Brutal Comeback in China by Susan Williams (Red Banner Reader no. 7); For a Century of People's Wars! Forward towards the Victory of Socialism and Communism! Published by Revolutionary Internationalist Movement; On the Party-Building Question Published by Potomac Socialist Organization; Should the Left Support McGovern? A Discussion Paper Issued by a Marxist-Leninist Study Group; Collective Works: Journal of Independent Marxist-Leninist Organizations, no. 4 (August 1975)
    - Movements, 1973-1979; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 121, Folder 2)
      For Working Class Unity and Black Liberation Published by October League (Marxist-Leninist); It's Right to Rebel! Lessons in the Struggle to Free Robert Smith, a Detroit Autoworker (A Call Pamphlet); Party Building in the U.S. Published by October League (Marxist-Leninist); Constitution of the October League (Marxist-Leninist)
    - Movements, 1943-1996; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      Labor Parties 1827-1834 by Alden Whitman; Who Will Speak for Labor? Issued by Labor Party Advocates of America; Manifesto for an American Revolutionary Party Published by National Organization for an American Revolution; Inflation: Are you Part of the Solution or Part of the Problem? Issued by National Organization for an American Revolution; How can You Stop it? Issued by American Socialist Organizing Committee; Call for Economic Justice: Labor Party Program Ratified by the Founding Labor Party Convention, June 6-9, 1996; Labor Parties in American History Published by United Electrical Radio & Machine Operators of America
    - Movements, 1926-1988; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      Truth about William Jennings Bryan by Clement Wood (Little Blue Book no. 1072); Is the Rainbow a real Alternative? A Socialist Response Published by Socialist Action; Rainbow and the Democratic Party: New Politics or Old? A Socialist Perspective Edited by Joanna Misnik Published by Solidarity; Stand Up and Be Counted: Why I Choose to Run by Henry Wallace Published by New Republic; Open Letter to Activists & Organizers of the Past and Present on the Need for a Mass Party of the People Issued by National Interim Committee for a Mass Party of the People; Eugene McCarthy on the Record: Excerpts from his Writings and Speeches Compiled by Dorothy Dunbar Published by Coalition for a Democratic Alternative; Give a Damn! Issued by Independent New Mexican Party [flyer]; Roadblock to Revolution: a Radical Critique of the Progressive Labor Party by Edward Greer and Charles Lengram
    - Movements, 1972-1975; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 121, Folder 5)
      Why People's Party? Issued by People's Party [flyer]; Dr. Spock – Common Sense for America Issued by People's Party [flyer]; Hobson for Vice-President Issued by People's Party [flyer]; Movement is not Enough! Published by the People's Party Press [flyer]; Why We do Not Support McGovern Issued by People's Party [flyer]; Why Should we Support a Party of Them When we Can Build a Party of Us? Issued by People's Party [flyer]; People's Convention, St. Louis, July 27-30 Published by National Office People's Party; People's Candidates Published by People's Party; Sexism: the People's Party National Convention Published by People's Party; Grass Roots Special Issue Published by People's Party; Up from the Roots! 1975 People's Party National Convention Call Published by People's Party; People's Party National Platform Adopted August 31, 1975 Published by People's Party
    - Movements, 1966-1995; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 121, Folder 6)
      What we Want by Stokely Carmichael Reprinted from New York Review of Books by Santa Clara County Friends of SNCC; 1967 High Tide of Black Resistance by James Forman Published by SNCC [Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee]; Toward Black Liberation by Stokely Carmichael Published by Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee; Legacy of Slavery and the Roots of Black Nationalism by Eugene D. Genovese; Groundings with my Brothers by Walter Rodney; Support the Black Freedom Movement in the South Issued by United League of Mississippi Fact Sheet [flyer]; Gangsters: a Solution to a Drug Problem in a Community by Larry Jamerson; Kwanzaa: Origin, Concepts, Practice by Maulana Karenga; Shaping Afrikan American Consciousness Issued by La Pena Cultural Center, Berkeley, California [program]; Black Scholar: Journal of Black Studies and Research, vol. 1, no. 7 (May 1970) Published by the Black World Foundation; Position and Progress of Black America: Some Pertinent Statistics by Thomas F. Mayer; In Defense of the Right to Political Secession for the Afro-American Nation: Papers and Resolutions from the School on the Afro-American National Question, September 1982; Grassroot Politics in Alabama Issued as Imani Special Issue February 1971 Published by Communications Workshop of the Black Allied Student Association at New York University
    - Movements, 1953-1994; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 121, Folder 7)
      Russian Revolution by Rosa Luxemburg, Translation and Introduction by Bertram Wolfe; Third World Nationalism by Sam Dolgoff Published by Anarchist Communist Federation of North America; My Social Credo by G.P. Maximoff (Rebel Worker Pamphlet no. 3); Fighting to Win: the History of an Anarchist Amongst a Thousand Others (Boris Dumont Booklet) Produced in Association with Anarchist Black Cross; Syndicalism: What it is by Gaylord Wilshire; Syndicalists in the Russian Revolution by G. P. Maximoff (Direct Actin Pamphlet no. 11) Published by Syndicalist Workers' Federation; British Syndicalism: Pages of Labour History by Tom Brown; Bureau of Public Secrets 1 (January 1976); White Collars & Horny Hands: the Revolutionary Thought of Waclaw Machajski by Max Nomad; Direct Action: an Outline of Workshop and Social Organisation by Wm Gallacher and J.R. Campbell (Reprints in Labour History no. 3); Shop Stewards and Workers' Control Published by Our Generation; Unions and Workers' Control Published by Our Generation; Free Time! The Case for a Shorter Workweek Published by Workers Solidarity Alliance; Origins of the Movement for Workers Councils in Germany 1918-29 Published by Our Generation
    - Movements, 1963-1966; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 146, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include material related to the Civil Rights movement: Negro History Week February 12-20, 1966 Alabama State Teachers Association; Fools and Cowards Cut Their Own Throats... Are American Workers Fools or Cowards?; Free At Last: A History of the Civil Rights Movement and Those Who Died in the Struggle; Last Hired, First Fired; Layoffs and Civil Rights; Freedom is a constant struggle... Defend victims of racism and repression; A Walking Tour of the Black Presence in San Francisco During the Nineteenth Century; The Negro in White Suburbia by Ian McMahan; Sugar Plum from the Cycle Cahawba Days.
    - Movements, 1965-1983; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 146, Folder 2)
      The materials in this folder relate to the Civil Rights movement: The Myth of Reverse Racism by International Committee Against Racism; Negro Representation A Step Towards Negro Freedom by Pettis Perry; "Letter from a Birmingham Jail + I have a Dream" by Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.; I Play Flute by Stembridge; Stop the Death Penalty Legal Lynching USA; A Brief Timeline of African-American Civil Rights 1909-1983; The War and the Negro People by James Ford; The White Problem; The Negro and Defense Council for Democracy; To Live Like Paul Robeson; The Fight to Implement Busing; The Treatment of Black Americans in Current Encyclopedias; Female Leadership in the Southern Civil Rights Struggel by Clara Fraser; My Son Joe, an appeal by Joseph Perlin; Mississippi From Within by Shirley Tucker.
    - Movements, 1970-1984; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 146, Folder 3)
      This folder contains material relating to the New Left: Welcome to Kentucky; The New Patriot Vol. 1 No. 4; 101 Reasons to Vote Against Ronald Reagan by Terence Cannon; Colonialism in Asia-Past adn Present by E.L. Wheelwright; The Unknown Marx by Martin Nicolaus; Historians and the New Deal by Brad Wiley; Unfair to Young People; Culture and Politics: notes from a conference by Barbara Bick; Military Reasearch at the University of Wisconsin on teh Topic of Biological Toxins.
    - Movements, 1958-2007; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 146, Folder 4)
      This fodlder contains material related to the Labor Movement: Plant Closures Myths, Realities and Responses by Gilda Haas; Why Child Labor Laws?; I Just Got Elected-Now What? by Bill Barry; Labor's Civil War in California by Cal Winslow; Union Democracy and Landrum Griffen; Your Job, Your Rights: An Introduction to Grievances and Union Representation; Democratic Rights in Federal Employment Unions by Herman Benson; Voices for Justice by Kent Wong; Outline for a Study of the History of Labor Unions in the United States by Sam Pollack; The Alliance of Certain Racketeer and Communist Dominated Unions in the Field of Transportation as a Threat to National Security; Electronics Workers Organize Vol. 1 No. 1.
    - Movements, 1946-1981; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 147, Folder 1)
      This folder contains material related to Trotskyism: The Russian Revoluation: A Balance Sheet of October by Ted Grant; The Ideas of Karl Marx by Alan Woods; Marxism and Religion by Alan Woods; Marxist Economics and Capitalist Crisis by Rob Sewell; Class Struggle and the American Revolution by John Peterson; Socialism and the Struggle for LGBT+ Equality; China's Long March to Capitalism; Frequently Asked Questions About Marxism by John Peterson; Only Victorious Socialist Revolutions Can Prevent the Third World War!; An OPen Letter to Dean Acheson "The Marine Corporal is Right!" by Max Shachtman; Proletariat No. 3; Proletariat No. 2; Yout Want Jobs; Problems of the Fourth International by G. Healy.
    - Movements, 1932-1979; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 147, Folder 2)
      This folder contains material related to the Prison movement: Women and Imprisonment by Nancy Kurshan; Voices from Within the Prison Walls by D.A. Sheldon; Fascism its most advanced form is here in America by George Jackson; Marion Mind Control Prison of Today; Southern Movement Still Life; Gary Lawton; The Kite Anti-Prison Newsjournal; On the Chain Gang by John L. Spivak.
    - Movements, 1935-1987; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 147, Folder 3)
      This folder contains material related to the Labor movement: Union Strategies for Hard Times by Bill Barry; Laurel Strike is Broken; Textile Facts; Our American Dreyfus Case by Lillian Symes; Child Labor in Mississippi by A.J. McKelway; The Rise of Organized Labor; Union Democracy in the Construction Trades; Background of the American Labor Movement by William O. Kuhl; How to Get an Honest Union Election by Herman Benson; Union Democracy, American Democracy, and Global Democracy: An Overview and Assessment by Michael J. Goldberg; Pride at Work Organizing for Lesbian and Gay Rights in Unions by Miriam Frank and Desma Holcomb; Capitalism: It's Development in the U.S. by Albert Parsons; On the Rise; Employee Rights and Employment Policy Journal and Michael Goldberg; How to Win Past Practice Grievances by Robert Schwartz.
    - Movements, 1937-1992; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 147, Folder 4)
      This folder contains material related to the Labor movement: Stopping Sexual Harassment: A Handbook for union and workplace activities; Labor and the American Way; The Work of the International Labor Defense for Aid to Labor's Prisoners and to Maintain and Enlarge Democratic Rights; The American Labor Movement by Leo Wolman; The Debates in Labor: Danger of Historic Opportunity? by Scott Marshall; Worker sin the Changing South by Nelson Blackstock; USA: The Labor Revolt of the 1960s by Stan Weir; Stopping Sexual Harrasment A Handbook by Elissa Clarke.
    - Movements, 1933-2000; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 148, Folder 1)
      This folder contains material related to Troskyism: The Moscow-Peking Dispute and the 4th International; Negroes Should Oppose the War by J.R. Johnson; In Defense of Black Nationalism by Tony Thomas; Ten Years by Max Shachtman; Socialism After Stalinism; The Communist Party at the Croassroad by H.W. Dewson; Marxism at the Millenium by Tony Cliff.
    - Movements, 1990-1993; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 148, Folder 2)
      The material in this folder relates to Trotskyism: In Memoriam Richard S. Fraser; War and the Workers by John West; China's Alliance with US Imperialism; Statues of teh Fourth Internationalism; Yugoslavia, East Europe and the Fourth International: The Evolution of Pabloist Liquidationism by Jan Norden.
    - Movements, 1970-2007; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 148, Folder 3)
      The material in this folder relates to the Labor movement: Corporate Power and the American Dream; Take a Good Look California Unemployment Insurance by Allan Rosenfield; Fare Strike San Francisco 2005; Fighting White Supremacy: A Poison in the Labor Movement by N. Jackson; Pickets at City Hall; For Democracy Where We Work by David Deleon; Plant Clsoings; Starting Over (Surviving a Plant Closure).
    - Movements, 1953-2017; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 148, Folder 4)
      This folder contains material realted to Trotskyism; But what about the workers?; Afro-Asian Revolutions by Raya Dunayevskaya; The Philosophic Moment of Marxist-Humanism by Raya Dunayevskaya; Black Nationalism and Marxist Theory; Edward Heisler, the SWP and the Assassination of Tom Henehan; The Fight for a Labor Party; Revolutionary Internationalism and the Struggle for Socialism in the United States; The Black-Red Conference; Marxism for the Sixties.
    - Movements, 1933-2000; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 149, Folder 1)
      This folder contains material related to Communism: Program of the Communist International; 300 Million Slaves and Serfs by Jurgen Kuczynski; Communism and the Family by Alexander Kollantani; The Most Burning Question Unity of Action by Bela Kun; The Revolutionary Family Movement in the Colonies; Youth and Facsism by O. Kuusinen; Resolutions Seventh Congress of the Communist International by G. Dimitroff; Capitalist Stabalization has Ended; The Struggle Against Imperialist War by Georgi Dimitroff; The Struggle Against Imperialist War and the Tasks of the Communists; The Second International in Dissolution by Bela Kun; Silent War and Bitter Peace: The Revolution in Austria by John Boyer; The Revolutionary Girl with the Titus-Head: Women's Participation in the Revolutions in Budapest and Munich in the Eyes of their Contemporaries by Eliza Johnson; The International Working Men's Association I.W.M.A; The IWA Today by C. Longmore.
    - Movements, 1926-1970; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 149, Folder 2)
      This folder contains material related to Socialism: Which Road for American Workers, Socialist or Communist? by Norman Thomas; What is Inudstrial Democracy? by Norman Thomas; War As a Socialist Sees It by Norman Thomas; Why Unemployment? by John Keracher; Conscription The Test of the Peace by Norman Thomas; Present-Day Socialism by Morris Hilquit; Something Better than Dumbarton Oaks by Norman Thomas; Emancipation Youth From Toil Old Age from Fear by Norman Thomas; RRussia... Promise and Performance by Norman Thomas; War Government and Peace by Norman Thomas; Is the New Deal Socialism? by Norman Thomas; As the Others See Us; Proletarian Democracy vs. Dictatorships and Despotism by Arnold Petersen; Why We Need Socialism in America by Michael Harrington; The French Revolution by A.J. Muste.
    - Movements, 1947-2005; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 149, Folder 3)
      The materials in this folder relate to Socialism: The Right to Be Lazy by Paul Lafargue; Money and Money Reforms by Christ Jelset; The Truth About Readers Digest by Sender Garlin; Why I am a Socialist by Norman Thomas; The Religion of Capital by Paul Lafargue; Democracy versus Dictatorship by Norman Thomas; Russia - Democracy or Dictatorship? by Norman Thomas; Which Offers More for the Future? by Norman Thomes; The New Deal by Norman Thomes; The Moral Basis of Modern Socialism by Ken Boss and Tom Tucker.
    - Movements, 1938-2004; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 149, Folder 4)